Nisha Kumari Senior UX Designer

+49 17675919268 in nisha-kumari-de 🙋 portfolio

Senior UX Designer with 8 years of experience in SaaS, web, mobile, and HMI design. Based in Berlin, I excel at creating intuitive interfaces that boost efficiency and user satisfaction. Strong communicator with a keen eye for design trends and technologies.

P Skills

User Research:

- User Interviews
- Data Analysis
- Storytelling
- Hypothesis
 Validation
- Cognitive
 Walkthrough
- Usability Testing
- Heuristic Analysis

Design

- Design Thinking
- Design System
- Design Variables & Tokens
- Wireframes & Mockups
- User Flows
- Prototyping
- Accessibility

Platform Expertise

- Websites
- Web Apps & Dashboards
- SaaS
- Mobile Applications
- Human Machine Interface (HMI)

Tools

- Figma
- Miro
- Dovetail
- Maze
- Pendo
- Google Analytics
- Notion
- Jira

Sep 2024 - present | Berlin, Germany

Confluence

Work Experience

Flexera

Senior UX Designer

• Designing Al-driven cloud cost anomaly detection for B2B FinOps users, enhancing real-time cost monitoring in the CCO(Cloud Cost Optimization) product.

• Enhancing the Automation product, enabling custom policies for optimized incident handling and cloud cost management.

Royal Cyber Inc

Senior UX Designer

Feb 2023 – Jun 2024 | Berlin - Remote

- Led UX design for a B2B SaaS cloud security and posture management product, enabling vulnerability identification and compliance remediation, resulting in a 30% reduction in security incidents.
- Designed B2B AI automation testing and event management apps, improving workflows.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define design strategies and align solutions with business objectives.
- Designed scalable design systems and style guides for consistent product experiences.

3DesignThinkers

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023 | Berlin - Remote

Freelance UX Researcher

- Led user research initiatives for an e-learning platform offering design and preparatory courses.
- Developed a qualitative UX research strategy using user interviews to extract insights and create recommendations for Jobs to Be Done, friction points, and prioritization.

Wipro Limited

Senior UX Designer

Nov 2019 - Jul 2022

Pune, India & Czech Republic

- Conducted in-depth user research to understand user behaviors and preferences, enabling the creation of low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototypes. These efforts significantly improved the HMI usability for Manufacturing Execution Systems (MES).
- Engaged in agile practices and scrum framework, fostering collaborative teamwork and efficient project execution.

Project Engineer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2019 | Pune, India

• Developed REST clients for e-commerce web development and collaborated closely with the UX designers for seamless integration.

Selected Work

Spektrum Akademie Zeitplaner 🔗

- Conducted user interviews and stakeholder consultations to understand the needs of admins, teachers, and students, iteratively refining wireframes and high-fidelity designs for usability and accessibility.
- Designed scheduling solutions that significantly reduced manual tracking efforts by 90%.

Mqtizer - Cross-Platform MQTT Client for Industrial-Grade IoT Solutions &

- Gathered valuable user feedback and conducted thorough usability tests, leading to user-driven enhancements and improved app functionality, **enhancing user retention by 25%.**
- Designed and optimized commercial website and marketing collateral for MQTIZER

VisionarAI - AI for Visionaries @

Secured 2nd place in the "soonami.io GmbH Cohort 0 Hackathon"

- Crafted intuitive user-centric experience for VisionarAI, utilizing insights from Y Combinator resources, aiding founders in product discovery.
- Collaborated with developers to simplify complex features for user-friendly interfaces and seamless interaction.

Education

Google UX Design Specialization

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022 | Berlin, Germany

Coursera

Bachelor's degree: Electronics and Communications Engineering ITM Gwalior

2012 - 2016 | Gwalior, India

Languages

English: Proficient | Hindi: Native | German: Learning A1